<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Page on ilikechicken</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/</link><description>Recent content in Home Page on ilikechicken</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://ilikechicken.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cu There</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/cu-there/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/cu-there/</guid><description>Winner of Best Beginner in NHacks VII.
Inspiration Our team searched for an idea for the student service app for this hackathon. During this process, we were quite perplexed because of the fact that many of the ideas were already put into effect on other apps. While I was thinking about how my sister was graduating high school, I thought about how stressful it was to be a student heading into a post-secondary environment.</description></item><item><title>EntryMail</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/email-checker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/email-checker/</guid><description>Inspiration When we&amp;rsquo;re thinking of our problems in school, the notion of clubs arose. Unfortunately, our school clubs were not managed thoroughly and were not secure, and trolls and anonymous users will often disrupt the club on the club Discord server. That&amp;rsquo;s when the idea for EntryEmail was conceived.
What it does Since clubs mostly take place in discord servers, we believed that our project should be related to discord. So we created a discord bot that allows for secure verification in the form of email.</description></item><item><title>Format numbers in Javascript</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/format-numbers-in-js/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/format-numbers-in-js/</guid><description>Now, you can just use .toLocaleString() to format a number in any way you like. Back then you would need a custom function to do that for you, now you can do it directly. Just call this function and it will return the string for you, and you can print it or save it for later use.</description></item><item><title>Git Logging Github Accounts With 2FA</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/git-logging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/git-logging/</guid><description>if you have 2FA for your Github account activated, it will be annoying to access your private repositories through git, since your password wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore.
What you want to do is that to make a token specifically for whatever you are doing. Go to settings -&amp;gt; developer settings -&amp;gt; tokens and generate the token. With the token, you can now login in through git. Make sure to save the token somewhere if you want to use it again as it won&amp;rsquo;t appear on the website again and you can only generate a new token.</description></item><item><title>How to connect to github</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/connect-to-github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/connect-to-github/</guid><description>When using git, it is a hassle to retype the password every time we commit. Of course, you can always save the password locally on the disk, like this:
git config credential.helper store The problem with this method is that the password is stored in plain text locally, which can be a security concern if your device gets stolen.
A more secure method would be to set a time-out for the password cache.</description></item><item><title>How to connect to your Pythonanywhere database remotely</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/remote-pythonanywhere-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/remote-pythonanywhere-database/</guid><description>Pythonanywhere is an excellent place to run your python code and your website, it offers multiple consoles and database.
When you are debugging your code, and it uses a database, such as a website, it can be quite tedious to set up another mysql server when you don’t have another cloud service such as Azure or AWS. In that case, you can just use the database from Pythonanywhere.
The database can’t be directly connected, so that you would need SSH tunneling.</description></item><item><title>How to dupilicate a python list</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/duplicate-list-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/duplicate-list-in-python/</guid><description>If you want a copy of a list, you might do this:
list1 = list2 if you alter values in list2, you would find that the values in list1 also changed. This is because that list2 is a shallow copy of list1.
A shallow copy is when you only copy the reference of a variable, meaning that list1 and list2 are essentially the same variables, just that it has two different names.</description></item><item><title>How to freely and accurately OCR PDFs</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/ocr-pdfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/ocr-pdfs/</guid><description>Many times when someone sends you a pdf of a scanned or a picture of a document, you can&amp;rsquo;t copy texts off of the pdf, nor searching for keywords. It becomes very frustrating to process the document. Here is something I found that can easily make computers process the work.
I searched many &amp;ldquo;free online OCR scanners&amp;rdquo;, but they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to work very well. After some research, I found: ocrmypdf.</description></item><item><title>How to get a procedure's definition in MSSQL</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/get-procedure-definition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/get-procedure-definition/</guid><description>If you are new to a legacy database and want to learn more about its internals, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s good to read the definitions of stored procedures. It can teach you what standard to follow and how exactly are the data stored. To do this, run the following query:
sp_helptext PROCEDURE This should get you the definitions.</description></item><item><title>How to make elements fixed on the screen</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/element-fixed-on-screen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/element-fixed-on-screen/</guid><description>If you want something to always float on the screen, not affected by other elements, you can achieve this using CSS:
.element{ position: fixed, } This way, you can set an element to be fixed on the screen.</description></item><item><title>How to strip html tags in Django</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/django-strip-html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/django-strip-html/</guid><description>Many times, you would want to strip the html tags away from a string and only leave plain text. This can be accomplished by using libraries such as BeautifulSoup, but it can also be accomplished using regex:
String target = someString.replaceAll(&amp;#34;&amp;lt;[^&amp;gt;]*&amp;gt;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;#34;); Syntax can be different depending on the language, but it should look something like that. Django already has a built-in function for this. It uses regex as well for less hassle.</description></item><item><title>ilikechicken.me</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/ilikechicken-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/ilikechicken-me/</guid><description>About Me I&amp;rsquo;m a high schooler living in Toronto who is highly interested in CS. I liked to tinker with computers when I was really young and kept the interest until now. I&amp;rsquo;m looking for any CS-related volunteer or intern opportunities, as well as learning more about the field and the future of technology. If you have any questions or want to get in touch, please feel free to contact me.</description></item><item><title>IMHP</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/imhp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/imhp/</guid><description>About the Job Worked as a web developer internship for a branch of sickkids, IMHP Used framework such as React, Material-UI, and server-end RESTful API development Worked on a team of 5 to develop a web application for a client Can ask for recommendation letter if needed</description></item><item><title>Lexis</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/lexis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/lexis/</guid><description>Winner of Best Design in LaunchHacks.
Inspiration While we were brainstorming ideas on what we wanted to base our project on for this hackathon, we thought about creating a game that was both fun and educational. We were quite puzzled when confronted with such a simple yet challenging idea. Our team went through countless games that established these two concepts. I thought about how my younger brother had trouble in English class because of the daunting imposition of learning confusing vocabulary.</description></item><item><title>Manim: An Python Animation Engine</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/manim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/manim/</guid><description>If you use Python, you might know a library called Manim. It is first a personal project by 3b1b and you can now (well it always has been open source, but it finally got usable documentation and maintenance recently, around 2020) use it for yourself as well.
There are two main versions of manim:
3b1b/manim: A version that is used and maintained by 3b1b himself, used in his Youtube videos. ManimCommunity: forked from manim in 2020, more stable, document, etc.</description></item><item><title>Recispeed</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/recispeed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/recispeed/</guid><description>Recispeed Our team is always frustrated when a crucial ingredient is missing while going through recipe books. This is why we developed this reverse search recipe app. In this app, you input everything you have, and it will return a list of recipes you can follow. This app is developed with React and ChakraUI, and dockerized and deployed on hop.io. Hop really made my life a lot easier, because it simplified all the complicated deployment and scales automatically.</description></item><item><title>Sat Preper</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/sat-preper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/sat-preper/</guid><description>A timer that records stats for SAT/ACT. It records the time you took for each question, and it visualizes the data after the test for you to improve your score.</description></item><item><title>Timezone Converter</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/tools/timezone-converter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/tools/timezone-converter/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uconnect</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/uconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/uconnect/</guid><description>About the Job “Bridging the gap between resource disadvantage and capability to inform future changemakers about the perfect school for them.”
Founded by grade 11 student Alfred Shi and other members, UConnect is an organization that informs students about post-secondary education and offers options to fit schools. We at UConnect recognize the privilege that came with private education–and the consequent gap between resource disadvantage and capability for other students across the world.</description></item><item><title>What Is GraphQL</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/graphql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/graphql/</guid><description>GraphQL is a new data API developed by Facebook. It can be added directly to your existing databases and provides a clear way to request data. For example, if you want everyone&amp;rsquo;s name in the database, you can just do:
Query query { People { Name Age } } It is a lot easier to use compared to traditional REST APIs. The best thing is, you can use more than one database.</description></item><item><title>What is MOSS and How to Use It</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/what-is-moss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/what-is-moss/</guid><description>If you are a computer science teacher or professor, one of the problems you might have is when your students copy code from each other. Or if you are investigating someone&amp;rsquo;s code and you want a trustworthy way to compare codes. MOSS, a code similarity check tool developed by a Stanford student, might help you out here.
MOSS stands for Measure Of Software Similarity. It compares two pieces of code and will make a judgment on whether any code looks similar or not.</description></item><item><title>WSL2: WSL but better</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/wsl2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/blogs/wsl2/</guid><description>the new WSL(Windows Subsystem Linux) is a nice tool for developers to test and develop projects on a simulated Linux kernel on Windows without running a full VM. Doing so has many advantages such as requiring less computing power, better file access, etc.
However, it is not perfect. You might run into weird environment issues because it is not a full Linux distro after all. For example, 32bit applications cannot run in WSL1, as well as many other limitations.</description></item></channel></rss>