<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on ilikechicken</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on ilikechicken</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cu There</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/cu-there/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/cu-there/</guid><description>Winner of Best Beginner in NHacks VII.
Inspiration Our team searched for an idea for the student service app for this hackathon. During this process, we were quite perplexed because of the fact that many of the ideas were already put into effect on other apps. While I was thinking about how my sister was graduating high school, I thought about how stressful it was to be a student heading into a post-secondary environment.</description></item><item><title>EntryMail</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/email-checker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/email-checker/</guid><description>Inspiration When we&amp;rsquo;re thinking of our problems in school, the notion of clubs arose. Unfortunately, our school clubs were not managed thoroughly and were not secure, and trolls and anonymous users will often disrupt the club on the club Discord server. That&amp;rsquo;s when the idea for EntryEmail was conceived.
What it does Since clubs mostly take place in discord servers, we believed that our project should be related to discord. So we created a discord bot that allows for secure verification in the form of email.</description></item><item><title>ilikechicken.me</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/ilikechicken-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/ilikechicken-me/</guid><description>About Me I&amp;rsquo;m a high schooler living in Toronto who is highly interested in CS. I liked to tinker with computers when I was really young and kept the interest until now. I&amp;rsquo;m looking for any CS-related volunteer or intern opportunities, as well as learning more about the field and the future of technology. If you have any questions or want to get in touch, please feel free to contact me.</description></item><item><title>IMHP</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/imhp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/imhp/</guid><description>About the Job Worked as a web developer internship for a branch of sickkids, IMHP Used framework such as React, Material-UI, and server-end RESTful API development Worked on a team of 5 to develop a web application for a client Can ask for recommendation letter if needed</description></item><item><title>Lexis</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/lexis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/lexis/</guid><description>Winner of Best Design in LaunchHacks.
Inspiration While we were brainstorming ideas on what we wanted to base our project on for this hackathon, we thought about creating a game that was both fun and educational. We were quite puzzled when confronted with such a simple yet challenging idea. Our team went through countless games that established these two concepts. I thought about how my younger brother had trouble in English class because of the daunting imposition of learning confusing vocabulary.</description></item><item><title>Recispeed</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/recispeed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/recispeed/</guid><description>Recispeed Our team is always frustrated when a crucial ingredient is missing while going through recipe books. This is why we developed this reverse search recipe app. In this app, you input everything you have, and it will return a list of recipes you can follow. This app is developed with React and ChakraUI, and dockerized and deployed on hop.io. Hop really made my life a lot easier, because it simplified all the complicated deployment and scales automatically.</description></item><item><title>Sat Preper</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/sat-preper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/sat-preper/</guid><description>A timer that records stats for SAT/ACT. It records the time you took for each question, and it visualizes the data after the test for you to improve your score.</description></item><item><title>Uconnect</title><link>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/uconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://wwww.ilikechicken.me/portfolio/uconnect/</guid><description>About the Job “Bridging the gap between resource disadvantage and capability to inform future changemakers about the perfect school for them.”
Founded by grade 11 student Alfred Shi and other members, UConnect is an organization that informs students about post-secondary education and offers options to fit schools. We at UConnect recognize the privilege that came with private education–and the consequent gap between resource disadvantage and capability for other students across the world.</description></item></channel></rss>